Fremont Rider Autograph Collection
Fremont Rider Autograph Collection
1826-1953
Rider, Fremont, 1885-1962.
391 items.
Papers of the American librarian, periodical editor. Collection includes autographed letters, signed documents, postcards, and a drawing; individuals represented include scholars, politicians, diplomats, social reformers, authors, and more. Includes letters collected by Rider as well as his own correspondence.
149543
Biographical History
Arthur Fremont Rider (1885-1962) was an American editor, author and librarian.
Born in Trenton, New Jersey, the son of George Arthur and Charlotte Elizabeth (Meader) Rider, he was educated in the public schools in Middletown, Connecticut and later in Syracuse, New York. He graduated from Syracuse University in 1905 with a PhB (Bachelor of Philosophy) and went on to the New York State Library School in Albany. Syracuse University awarded him the honorary LHD (Doctor of Humane Letters) in 1937.
Rider's first career as editor and publisher began in 1907. Over the course of more than thirty years, he served as associate editor of The Delineator, editor of The Monthly Book Review for nearly ten years, managing editor of Publisher's Weekly, editor of The American Library Annual, and managing editor of Library Journal. During World War I he published the International Military Digest, which he edited at the United States Military Academy. From 1914-1933 he was president of the Rider Press, periodicals printers in New York City, and for a time was associated with B. W. Dodge & Co., publishers.
In 1933 he was named Librarian of Wesleyan University's Olin Library, a position he retained until his retirement in 1953. He was the author of numerous magazine articles and books, including a biography of Melvil Dewey. He wrote on library policy, among other subjects, and in his book The Scholar and the Future of the Research Library (1944) he was an early proponent of microcard technology. Not content with the theoretical, he was also the inventor of a book truck, stack shelving, and other library equipment.
As chairman of the American Genealogical Index from 1934, and as founder (1951) of the Godfrey Memorial Library (which he continued to direct after his retirement from Wesleyan), he was a leader in the assembly of American genealogical data.
Fremont Rider married his first wife, Grace Godfrey, on October 21, 1908; he and his second wife, Marie Gallup (Ambrose), were married on June 6, 1951.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Fremont Rider Autograph Collection comprises 391 items mounted in ten binders. Items range from letters and notes to postcards, signed documents, and at least one drawing, and span more than one hundred years (1826-1953). Each page gives additional information about the writer such as his or her profession or notable accomplishments, and portions of this information have been transferred to the inventory below. The information on the pages in the binders is Rider's own and has not been altered; the inventory below, however, has been supplemented where appropriate with additional research.
Of the 391 items in the collection, 264 are addressed to Rider, 125 are addressed to other correspondents, and there are two odd items (see Moffatt and Rice). The collection contains no letters from Fremont Rider himself.
The collection contains letters written to Fremont Rider personally, to the Rider Press, or to him as Wesleyan University Librarian, as well as autographs and signed items that he "happened upon casually," as he said in a letter (25 Jun 1954) to Wharton Miller of the Syracuse University Library, explaining that he had never been an assiduous collector. Among the correspondents are Sherwood Anderson, Rex Beach, James Warner Bellah, Melvil Dewey, Theodore Dreiser, John Nance Garner, Francis Hackett, Jack London, John L. Lewis, Christopher Morley, Eleanor Roosevelt, Alfred E. Smith, Rex Stout, Robert A. Taft, Booth Tarkington, Countess Alexandra Tolstoy, and Sumner Welles.
The earliest item in the collection is an 1826 certificate of ordination signed by Thomas C. Brownell, a Connecticut Episcopal bishop. The earliest letter, dated August 25, 1831, is signed "Hanniball" and is addressed to the noted slave leader Nat Turner. (Its authenticity has not been established.) In a 1922 postcard Franklin Delano Roosevelt answered a publisher's inquiry by stating that his reading interests centered around the U.S. Navy. Many of the other letters are from Episcopal bishops and other members of the clergy, authors, librarians, publishers, or individuals associated with colleges or universities.
Other letters not addressed to Fremont Rider include those from Irving Bacheller, Richard Harding Davis, Eugene Debs, William Lloyd Garrison, Robert LaFollette, William Howard Taft, and Stewart Edward White. Among the recipients of these letters are B. D. Godfrey of Newtonville, Massachusetts, and Edward Campion Acheson and Richard Lawrence DeZeng, both of Middletown, Connecticut.
The collection also includes a detailed card index listing each item with name of sender, recipient, date and other pertinent information.
Arrangement of the Collection
Items are arranged alphabetically by name of sender.
Related Material
has several other collections of autographs. See for example the following:
Argosy Autograph Collection
Frances Ward Harrington Autograph Collection
Graeme O'Geran Presidential Autograph Collection
Howes Norris Jr. Autograph Cartoon Collection
Gordon N. Ray Collection of Victorian Autographs
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- British; Rider, Fremont, 1885-1962 -- Archives.; Authors -- Autographs.; Autographs -- Collectors and collections.; Bishops -- Autographs.; Clergy -- Autographs.; Deans, Cathedral and collegiate -- Autographs.; Governors -- Autographs.; Novelists -- Autographs.; Politicians -- Autographs.; Social reformers -- Autographs.; Autographs.; Correspondence.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Fremont Rider, 1954, with some later additions.
Inventory
- Autographs
  - Acheson, Edward Campion, August 21, 1909; November 15, 1918; Bishop, Episcopal Diocese of Connecticut (Box 1)
  - Adams, Arthur, July 7, 1934; October 24, 1949; Librarian, Trinity College (Box 1)
  - Aitken, Robert Grant, June 29, 1925; Assoc. Director, Lick Observatory (Box 1)
  - Alsop, Stewart Johonnett Oliver, May 30, 1946; journalist, political analyst (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Edwin Hatfield, December 29, 1933; Director, New York Public Library (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, November 15 [no year]; author (Box 1)
  - Bacheller, Irving, September 10, 1909; journalist (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Robert L., March 4, 1932; U.S. Representative (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Louis Jonathan, April 1, 1921; Librarian, Gary Public Library (Box 1)
  - Baker, George Barr, November 21, 1907; Assoc. editor, Everybody's Magazine (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Raymond Earl, February 3, 1940; Governor of Connecticut (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Roger Sherman, July 24, 1944; Attorney (Box 1)
  - Ball, Thomas Raymond, April 27, 1939; U.S. Representative (Box 1)
  - Beach, Rex Ellingwood, January 26, 1918; President, Authors League of America (Box 1)
  - Bellah, James Warner, September 24, 1936; author of Westerns (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Clare, November 3 [no year]; chess patron (Box 1)
  - Bertram, James, June 17, 1914; Secretary, Carnegie Corporation (Box 1)
  - Blatch, Harriet Stanton, February 16, 1936; writer, women's suffrage activist (Box 1)
  - Bloom, Sol, April 26, 1932; U.S. Representative (Box 1)
  - Borden, Fanny, October 10, 1933; Librarian, Vassar University (Box 1)
  - Bowerman, George Franklin, May 24, 1922; Library, District of Columbia (Box 1)
  - Bowman, Isaiah, January 31, 1917; Director, American Geographical Society (Box 1)
  - Boyer, Norman, September 14, 1909; editor[?}, The Smart Set (Box 1)
  - Brandegee, Frank B., January 6, 1920; U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Box 1)
  - Branscomb, Bennett Harvie, September 1, 1938; Association of American Colleges (Box 1)
  - Brett, George Platt, October 27, 1916; July 2, 1923;; April 16, 1924; President, The MacMillan Company (Box 1)
  - Brewster, Chauncey Bunce, April 17, 1901; December 10, 1913; Bishop, Episcopal Diocese of Connecticut (Box 1)
  - Brown, Alice, October 6, 1908; novelist, poet, playwright (Box 1)
  - Brown, Charles Harvey, January 18, 1941; Librarian, Iowa State College (Box 1)
  - Brown, Kenneth, March 15, 1908; author? (Box 1)
  - Brownell, Thomas Church, June 7, 1826; Bishop of the Episcopal Church, founder of Trinity College in Hartford, CT (Box 1)
  - Brownson, Carleton, January 29, 1923; Dean, College of the City of New York (Box 1)
  - Butler, Benjamin Franklin, October 2, 1883; Governor of Massachusetts (Box 1)
  - Butler, Ellis Parker, January 19, 1917; author (Box 1)
  - Cadman, Samuel Parkes, March 13, 1926; Chairman, Churches, American Guardian Association (Box 1)
  - Caldwell, George B., August 18, 1920; President, Sperry & Hutchinson (Box 1)
  - Camp, E., July 3, 1925; Director of Customs, Dept of the Treasury (Box 1)
  - Capper, Arthur, April 26, 1921; U.S. Senator (Box 1)
  - Chancellor, William Estabrook, undated; academic and author (Box 1)
  - Civil War soldier, name unknown, Nov 1862 (Box 1)
  - Claflin, Horace Brigham, July 1, 1873; July 28, 1882; merchant and businessman (Box 1)
  - Claflin, William, January 3, 1869; Governor of Massachusetts (Box 1)
  - Clayton, William, undated (Box 1)
  - Comfort, Will Levington, October 16, 1916; author of adventure novels (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Frederic Taber, July 22, 1929; August 4, 1930; author and editor (Box 1)
  - Cross, Wilbur Lucius, March 30, 1937; Governor of Connecticut (Box 1)
  - Crowninshield, Frank, October 8, 1930; Editor, Vanity Fair (Box 1)
  - Curtis, Florence R., October 10, 1933; Director, Library School, Hampton Institute (Box 1)
  - Danton, Joseph Periam, November 17, 1936; Librarian, Temple University (Box 1)
  - Davenport, Frederick Morgan, November 21, 1938; President, National Institute of Public Affairs (Box 1)
  - Davenport, Homer Calvin, March 11, 1929; to Theodore Dreiser (Box 1)
  - Davey, Martin L., November 29, 1919; U.S. Representative (Box 1)
  - Davey, Martin L., December 1, 1919; U.S. Representative (Box 1)
  - Davies, Thomas Frederick, February 25, 1913; Bishop, Episcopal Diocese of Western Massachusetts (Box 1)
  - Davies, Thomas Frederick, April 28, 1913; February 22, 1913;; May 7, 1913;; June 26, 1917; Bishop, Episcopal Diocese of Western Massachusetts (Box 1)
  - Davis, James John, January 18, 1924; U.S. Secretary of Labor (Box 1)
  - Davis, Richard Harding, June 12 [no year]; journalist, novelist (Box 1)
  - Davison, George Willets, January 21, 1932; April 6, 1937;; December 10, 1937; attorney, businessman (Box 1)
  - Dawson, Coningsby William, November 5, 1913; George H. Doran Co. (Box 1)
  - Day, Holman Francis, May 20 [no year]; editor, novelist (Box 1)
  - Day, Joseph P., April 26, 1932; auctioneer, real estate (Box 1)
  - Debs, Eugene, October 15, 1908; Presidential candidate, Socialist Party (Box 1)
  - DeLancey, William Heathcote, 3/30/1843; 8/20/1847; Bishop, Episcopal Diocese of Western New York (Box 1)
  - Deland, Margaret (Margaretta Wade, nee Campbell), March 9, 1917; novelist, poet (Box 1)
  - Dent, J., June 9, 1922; J. M. Dent & Sons (Box 1)
  - Dent, Joseph Malaby, August 11, 1922; British publisher of the "Everyman" imprint (Box 1)
  - Dewey, Godfrey, November 19, 1934; Lake Placid Club; proponent of 1932 Lake Placid Olympics (Box 1)
  - Dewey, Melvil, August 18, 1914; undated; librarian and educator (Box 1)
  - Dodge, B., February 24, 1924; May 6, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Doran, George H., October 26, 1916; June 9, 1922;; February 3, 1923; George H. Doran Co. (Box 1)
  - Doubleday, Frank Nelson, June 7, 1922; publisher (Box 1)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, November 16, 1910; undated; author (Box 1)
  - Dunham, Mary, February 23, 1934; Librarian, Smith College (Box 1)
  - Eastman, Linda A., July 26, 1934; Librarian, Cleveland Public Library (Box 1)
  - Eastman, William R., January 28, 1914; New York State Education Department (Box 1)
  - Eidlitz, Otto W., March 6, 1918; Housing Committee, Council of National Defense (Box 1)
  - Elder, Paul, February 11, 1925; March 4, 1925;; April 15, 1925;; May 5, 1925; Paul Elder & Co. (Box 1)
  - Ellsworth, William W., August 8, 1913; President, The Century Co. (Box 1)
  - Fackenthal, Frank D., July 7, 1923; Secretary of the University, Columbia University (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Irving, June 28, 1909; President, Committee of One Hundred (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Samuel H., February 13, 1935; Chairman, Connecticut Tercentenary Commission (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Samuel H., August 18, 1938; Chairman, Connecticut Tercentenary Commission (Box 1)
  - Fletcher, Duncan U., April 30, 1932; July 12, 1934; U.S. Senate, Commission on Banking and Currency (Box 1)
  - Flynn, W. J., February 17, 1917; Chief of the Treasury Department (Box 1)
  - Folks, Homer, July 22, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Forbes, B. C., May 12, 1932; Scottish financial journalist, founder of Forbes Magazine (Box 1)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, May 23, 1946; clergyman; Riverside Church (Box 1)
  - Freeman, Mary E. Wilkins, October 2, 1909; short story author and novelist (Box 1)
  - Garner, John Nance, March 2, 1932; U.S. House of Representatives, Speaker (Box 1)
  - Garrison, William Lloyd, April 4, 1878; journalist and reformer (Box 1)
  - Gates, Milo H., November 20, 1915; Vicar, Chapel of the Intercession, NY (Box 1)
  - Giddings, Franklin H., December 4, 1895; professor, sociologist, economist (Box 1)
  - Gillette, William, April 28, 1935; playwright? (Box 1)
  - Gillis, Mabel R., May 25, 1934; Librarian, California State Library (Box 1)
  - Glasgow, Ellen Anderson Gholson, November 22, 1908; Pulitzer prize-winning novelist (Box 1)
  - Godard, George S., July 26, 1923; August 2, 1923;; September 20, 1934; State Librarian, Hartford, CT (Box 1)
  - Goldberg, Isaac, March 30, 1937; journalist, editor, author (Box 1)
  - Goodrich, Arthur, June 7, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Gough, John B., November 12, 1875 (Box 1)
  - Greeley-Smith, Nicola, February 1, 1908; Editor[?}, The World (Box 1)
  - Green, Anna Katharine, September 12, 1908; poet and author of detective fiction (Box 1)
  - Green, Stephen H., December 8, 1899; Reverend (Box 1)
  - Greenbie, Marjorie, April 19, 1926; Mt. Holyoke College (Box 1)
  - Greer, David Hummell, January 16, 1893; November 23, 1915; Protestant Episcopal bishop.; St. Bartholomew's Rectory (Box 1)
  - Gregory, W. F., August 30, 1913; Manager, Lothrop Lee & Shepard (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Winifred, September 19, 1935; Editor, Union List of Newspapers (Box 1)
  - Griswold, Alexander, 1827; Bishop, Episcopal Eastern Diocese (Box 1)
  - Grosvenor, William M., October 30, 1916; Dean, Cathedral of St. John the Divine, New York (Box 1)
  - Hackett, Francis, August 9 [no year]; Irish author, critic [?] (Box 1)
  - Haldeman-Julius, Emanuel, June 30, 1932; reformer, publisher (Box 1)
  - Hall, Bolton, March 5, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Halsey, Forrest, undated; screenwriter (Box 1)
  - Hanniball, August 25, 1831; to Nat Turner, Suffolk, VA (Box 1)
  - Harcourt, Alfred, April 20, 1912; February 3, 1923;; June 29, 1923;; May 1, 1917; Henry Holt & Co. (Box 1)
  - Harriman, Karl Edward, December 3, 1921; Editor, Redbook Magazine (Box 1)
  - Hays, Will H., September 10, 1921; Postmaster General (Box 1)
  - Heidel, W. A., August 26, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Herbert, Victor, undated (Box 1)
  - Herrick, Robert, September 19, 1908; novelist; University of Chicago (Box 1)
  - Heye, George Gustav, July 7, 1923; Director, Museum of the American Indian (Box 1)
  - Hill, Frank P., December 28, 1914; November 19, 1934; Librarian, Brooklyn Public Library (Box 1)
  - Hoar, George F., October 1, 1883; U.S. Senator (Box 1)
  - Hochwalt, Frederick G., Reverend Monsignor, May 21, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Hoe, Richard March, May 30, 1882; R. Hoe & Co. (Box 1)
  - Holder, Charles Frederick, undated; naturalist, author, founder of Pasadena's Tournament of Roses (Box 1)
  - Holt, Hamilton, March 25, 1911; April 22, 1911;; May 23, 1946; President, Rollins College (Box 1)
  - Hopkins, Mary Alden, undated; author [?] (Box 1)
  - Hough, Emerson, July 17, 1904; author of Westerns (Box 1)
  - Howe, Louis McHenry, March 15, 1933; March 25, 1933; Secretary to President Roosevelt (Box 1)
  - Howe, Marshall, June 3, 1925; Asst. Director, NY Botanical Garden (Box 1)
  - Hoyem, Oliver, January 18, 1924; National Cathedral Foundation (Box 1)
  - Hoyns, Henry, February 6, 1931; President, Harper & Brothers (Box 1)
  - Hubbard, E. Kent, December 1, 1908; December 11, 1918;; February 13, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Hubsch, B. W., September 17, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Hurt, Peyton, April 22, 1939; Librarian, Williams College (Box 1)
  - Hyslop, James H., October 1, 1908; October 6, 1908; American Society for Psychical Research (Box 1)
  - Jewett, Frank Baldwin, June 11, 1946; American physicist, president of Bell Labs (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Burges, August 29, 1931; Director of Public Relations, Syracuse University (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Helen Louise, June 25, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Johnston, Albert W., December 8, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Johnston, Charles, October 6, 1908; University Club (Box 2)
  - Junker, Carl, December 28, 1908; Austrian author, General Secretary of the Central Association of the Austrian Book Trade. (Box 2)
  - Jzabo, Edwin, February 15, 1907; Librarian, City of Budapest (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Donald A., February 24, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Kauffman, Ruth, March 17, 1910 (Box 2)
  - Kennerley, Mitchell, May 11, 1915; British-born American publisher (Box 2)
  - Kent, Frank Richardson, October 20, 1943; The Baltimore Sun (Box 2)
  - Kenyon, William Squire, April 27, 1921; U.S. Senator (Box 2)
  - Keogh, Andrew, October 25, 1934; Librarian, Yale University (Box 2)
  - Keppel, Frederick Paul, December 11, 1936; Carnegie Corporation of New York (Box 2)
  - King, Willford I., April 22, 1932; statistician, economist, chairman of the Committee for Constitutional Government (Box 2)
  - King, William H., March 10, 1932; U.S. Senator (Box 2)
  - Kingsley, Florence M., September 7, 1908; author of Christian children's novels [?] (Box 2)
  - Kinsolving, G., November 14, 1899 (Box 2)
  - Knapp, Martin Augustine, January 21, 1904; Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 2)
  - La Follette, Robert Marion, September 8, 1908; U.S. Senator (Box 2)
  - Lane, William Coolidge, December 23, 1914; Librarian, Harvard University (Box 2)
  - Lanier, H., April 9, 1912; Editor, Doubleday, Page & Co. (Box 2)
  - Lauck, W. Jett, February 8, 1919; Secretary, National War Labor Board (Box 2)
  - Leffingwell, H., April 21, 1902; Reverend, Trinity Church, Toledo OH (Box 2)
  - Leidinge, ----, October 24, 1933; Librarian, Bayerische Staatsbibliothek, Munich (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Fulton Jr., December 11, 1953; conservative radio personality (Box 2)
  - Lewis, John Llewellyn, June 6, 1946; labor leader, president of United Mine Workers for 40 years (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Willard P., November 18, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig, November 19 [no year]; Jewish critic and novelist (Box 2)
  - London, Jack, July 27, 1909; author (Box 2)
  - Lonergan, Augustine, April 8, 1933; U.S. Senator (Box 2)
  - Lord, Milton Edward, December 11, 1933; December 2, 1936; Director, Boston Public Library (Box 2)
  - Lorimer, George Horace, May 3, 1934; Editor, The Saturday Evening Post (Box 2)
  - Losey, Frederick Douglas, April 7, 1916; October 25, 1916;; December 28, 1916; author, professor; director of the Boar's Head Dramatic Society (Syracuse University) (Box 2)
  - Lovejoy, Owen B., May 26, 1932; Secretary, Children's Aid Society (Box 2)
  - McConaughy, James L., June 1 [no year]; Governor of Connecticut (Box 2)
  - McCrum, Blanche Prichard, December 29, 1938; Librarian, Wellesley College (Box 2)
  - MacGrath, Harold, July 9, 1909 (Box 2)
  - MacGregor, T. D., April 28, 1922; November 2, 1922;; May 5, 1924; Vice President, Edwin Bird Wilson Inc. (Box 2)
  - Mackenzie, James C., undated; Mackenzie School (Box 2)
  - McMurtrie, Douglas C., May 14, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Maloney, Francis, April 30, 1941; U.S. Senator (Box 2)
  - Manchester, Earl N., July 31, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Marbury, Elisabeth, May 14, 1912; theatre and literary agent [?] (Box 2)
  - Marshall, L. C., March 11, 1920; Dean, School of Commerce and Administration, University of Chicago (Box 2)
  - Mason, C. E., May 8, 1929; Miss C. E. Mason's School (Box 2)
  - Masson, Thomas Lansing, July 21 [no year]; editor, professor of dramatic literature at Columbia (Box 2)
  - Matthews, James Brander, March 22, 1919; author, educator (Box 2)
  - Melcher, Frederic Gershom, January 4, 1924; publisher, bookseller, editor, creator of Newbery and Caldecott awards (Box 2)
  - Melish, John Howard, February 3, 1916; January 27, 1918; pastor, Church of the Holy Trinity, Brooklyn, NY (Box 2)
  - Merritt, Schuyler, July 5, 1919; U.S. Representative (Box 2)
  - Metcalf, Keyes, January 21, 1938; Librarian, Harvard University (Box 2)
  - Meyer, Agnes E. (Mrs. Eugene), May 24, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Mifflin, George Harrison, March 11, 1910; Houghton Mifflin Co. (Box 2)
  - Milam, Carl H., April 13, 1933; November 17, 1934; Secretary, American Library Association (Box 2)
  - Miller, Gerrit Smith, April 15, 1922; Smithsonian Institution (Box 2)
  - Mills, Ogden L., July 11, 1934; businessman, politician (Box 2)
  - Minnigerode, C. Powell, February 2, 1923; Director, Corcoran Gallery of Art (Box 2)
  - Mitchell, Silas Weir, October 14 [no year]; physician, author (Box 2)
  - Moffatt, ----, undated; artist; includes pencil sketch (Box 2)
  - Mohrhardt, Foster, February 20, 1940; Librarian, Washington and Lee University (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher Darlington, April 6, 1937; April 7, 1937;; April 16, 1937; journalist, novelist, poet (Box 2)
  - Morrow, William, March 13, 1922; June 7, 1922; Secretary, Frederick A. Stokes Co. (Box 2)
  - Muldoon, William, October 11, 1912; Hygienic Institute (Box 2)
  - Nichols, Harry Peirce, Reverend, November 22, 1915 (Box 2)
  - Nicholson, Meredith, July 1, 1909; author, politician, diplomat (Box 2)
  - Nicolson, Frank W., January 25, 1932; Dean, Wesleyan University (Box 2)
  - Nock, Albert Jay, December 10, 1923; Libertarian, author, critic (Box 2)
  - Oakes-Ochs, George Washington, September 10, 1928; American journalist; New York Times (Box 2)
  - Cohs, Adolph Simon, August 7, 1918; American journalist; New York Times (Box 2)
  - Olmsted, John Charles, August 10, 1901; Olmsted Brothers Landscape Architects (Box 2)
  - Oskison, John Milton, August 17, 1909; Collier's Magazine (Box 2)
  - Oswald, John Clyde, March 12, 1926; New York Employing Printers Association (Box 2)
  - Page, Arthur Wilson, December 10, 1917; Editor, Doubleday Page & Co. (Box 2)
  - Paine, Paul M., February 5, 1923; Librarian, Syracuse Public Library (Box 2)
  - Patterson, Mortimer B., February 22, 1936; Justice, Supreme Court of the State of New York (Box 2)
  - Patton, James G., June 24, 1946; President, Farmers Educational and Cooperative Union of America (Box 2)
  - Payne, Will, October 1, 1908 (Box 2)
  - Pearson, Edmund Lester, January 16, 1918; February 18, 1936;; January 9 [no year]; Librarian, true crime author (Box 2)
  - Perry, Everett R., June 29, 1925; July 28, 1925; Librarian, Los Angeles Public Library (Box 2)
  - Pettengill, Samuel B., March 31, 1933; U.S. Representative (Box 2)
  - Pharr, Clyde, December 1, 1926; professor of classics, Vanderbilt University (Box 2)